export const chapter = "Chapter - 8: Means of Transport";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What was the primary means of travel for early humans before the invention of the wheel?",
        optionA: "Carts with wheels",
        optionB: "Animals",
        optionC: "On foot",
        correctAnswer: "On foot",
      },
      {
        question: "Who made the first practical steam engine in 1712?",
        optionA: "Thomas Newcomen",
        optionB: "James Watt",
        optionC: "George Stephenson",
        correctAnswer: "Thomas Newcomen",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary mode of transport for people and goods in most countries?",
        optionA: "Air travel",
        optionB: "Trains",
        optionC: "Ships",
        correctAnswer: "Trains",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the largest railway network in Asia?",
        optionA: "China",
        optionB: "India",
        optionC: "Japan",
        correctAnswer: "India",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which type of transport is most suitable for bulky goods like food grains and petroleum?",
        optionA: "Road transport",
        optionB: "Air transport",
        optionC: "Water transport",
        correctAnswer: "Water transport",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the longest railway in India with a total length of 4,572 kilometers?",
        optionA: "Gatiman Express",
        optionB: "Mumbai Rajdhani",
        optionC: "NH-7 (Varanasi to Kanyakumari)",
        correctAnswer: "NH-7 (Varanasi to Kanyakumari)",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which canal links the Mediterranean Sea with the Red Sea, reducing travel distances for ships?",
        optionA: "Panama Canal",
        optionB: "Suez Canal",
        optionC: "Bering Strait",
        correctAnswer: "Suez Canal",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which means of transport is the latest and allows humans to 'fly like birds'?",
        optionA: "Trains",
        optionB: "Ships",
        optionC: "Airways",
        correctAnswer: "Airways",
      },
      {
        question: "What is the busiest seaport in India?",
        optionA: "Chennai",
        optionB: "Mumbai",
        optionC: "Kolkata",
        correctAnswer: "Mumbai",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What are the primary factors that cause variations in soil from region to region?",
        optionA: "Temperature and rainfall",
        optionB: "Soil erosion",
        optionC: "Plant diversity",
        correctAnswer: "Temperature and rainfall",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The invention of the wheel revolutionized _______.",
        optionA: "communication",
        optionB: "transportation",
        optionC: "agriculture",
        correctAnswer: "transportation",
      },
      {
        question:
          "All those vehicles that move on land like scooters, cars, and trucks are included in _______.",
        optionA: "air transport",
        optionB: "water transport",
        optionC: "land transport",
        correctAnswer: "land transport",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Roadways provide a link between railway stations, air, and sea ports and act as a _______ to other modes of transport.",
        optionA: "barrier",
        optionB: "connector",
        optionC: "competitor",
        correctAnswer: "connector",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Highways that connect major cities of a country are called _______ highways.",
        optionA: "local",
        optionB: "state",
        optionC: "national",
        correctAnswer: "national",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Pan-American Highway connects _______ in North America to Chile in South America.",
        optionA: "Alaska",
        optionB: "New York",
        optionC: "Los Angeles",
        correctAnswer: "Alaska",
      },
      {
        question:
          "India's road network is the second largest in the world, with a total length of over _______ kilometers.",
        optionA: "10,000",
        optionB: "30,000",
        optionC: "43.20 lakh",
        correctAnswer: "43.20 lakh",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The Golden Quadrilateral connects the major metropolitan cities of Mumbai, Chennai, Delhi, and Kolkata with a length of _______ kilometers.",
        optionA: "1,000",
        optionB: "2,500",
        optionC: "5,846",
        correctAnswer: "5,846",
      },
      {
        question:
          "In India, the longest railway is the _______ that stretches across Canada.",
        optionA: "Trans-Siberian Railway",
        optionB: "Grand Orient Express",
        optionC: "Trans-Canadian Highway",
        correctAnswer: "Trans-Canadian Highway",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Ships that carry perishable products like meat, milk, fruits, and flowers are called _______ ships.",
        optionA: "tanker",
        optionB: "cargo",
        optionC: "refrigerated",
        correctAnswer: "refrigerated",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The first successful aeroplane was built in 1903 by two American brothers, Wilbur Wright and Orville Wright, making air travel the most favorite mode of _______.",
        optionA: "transportation",
        optionB: "communication",
        optionC: "entertainment",
        correctAnswer: "transportation",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "The Earth's uppermost layer is called soil.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Soil is not essential for the growth of plants.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question: "Humus makes the soil less fertile.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Weathering is the process of rocks breaking down by the action of wind, water, and climate.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The characteristics of soil depend on the types of animals that live in it.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Alluvial soil is most fertile when found in the Ganga valley.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Black soil is mainly found in the Northern Plains of India.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Red soil gets its color from the iron found in its composition in a crystallized form.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question: "Yellow soil appears when red soil is dehydrated.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Soil's characteristics are not influenced by factors like temperature and rainfall.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
